MAUREEN DURNIN

415-672-0347 maureenmdurnin@gmail.com Portfolio LinkedIn Github

SKILLS JavaScript • Node.js • Ruby • Rails • React • Redux • PostgreSQL • SQL • MongoDB • Heroku • jQuery • CSS HTML • MapBox • Express.js • Git • AJAX • Webpack • REST API • HTTP • rSpec

PROJECTS

Viral | An interactive disease-tracking data visualization

live I repo

Technologies: PostgreSQL with Postgis, Javascript, Mapbox

- Employed Postgis software to generate pseudo-random coordinates, confined within state boundaries, to convey disease rate information.
- Authored strategic database queries & frontend storage logic to seamlessly re-render up to thousands of coordinates every 80ms.
- Utilized JavaScript asynchronous functions to automate filtered rerendering

TableFor2 | A restaurant reservation web app inspired by OpenTable

live I repo

Technologies: PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, React & Redux, Sass, Ajax

- Refined error handling with custom Rails validations and ActiveRecord search to prevent reservation overlap
- Implemented responsive UI, including image proportions respective to window resizing using CSS to ensure usability across devices
- Implemented filtered search by city and restaurant name using custom backend routes for tailored results.

GetYoked | An interactive web app which generates progressive workouts and tracks workout history

Technologies: MongoDB, Express.js, Axios, Node.js, CSS

- Employed custom routes to allow updates to user workout history using Express.js, ensuring a customized and progressive workout experience.
- Designed and implemented separate routes to successfully maintain a single randomized workout within front-end state shape.
- Implemented randomized workout generator based on user activity level and desired workout input using Express.js, incorporating choice into the user experience.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Frontend Developer

SpotAngels, SF (YC - S14)

Dec 2019 - Present

• Reimplemented the website payment page to increase usability and improve the funnel conversion by 30%.

Bartender

Valley Tavern, SF Oct 2017 - Aug 2019

• Applied excellent organizational and multitasking abilities to handle simultaneous customer, team and business needs while avoiding unnecessary delays or errors and maintaining an engaged, positive attitude.

Project Coordinator & DHS Liaison, Teen Decisions Study

University of Oregon, DSN Lab - UO Prevention Science Institute

Oct 2015 - Oct 2017

- Hired, trained and supervised research assistants on various study-related tasks, including recruitment, working with study participants, consenting procedures, confidentiality practices, and data management.
- Created and incorporated new experimental designs into preexisting study protocols with limited supervision. This required considerable attention to detail as the study was constrained by a grant funding timeline.

Membership Sales Representative

YMCA - Eugene OR, Chinatown SF, Richmond SF, and Presidio SF

June 2011 - June 2016

Effectively juggled the demands of our busy hub; giving tours, resolving issues, and offering friendly service.

EDUCATION

AppAcademy - 2019

University of Oregon - BS Psychology • Distinguished Graduate, Cum Laude • 2015